我们可以补充吗？
Can we refill?
¿Podemos rellenar?
这个想法，对吗？
The idea, right?
La idea, ¿no?
如果不是，那就不严重了。
If not, it's not serious.
Si no, no es serio.
一个小弓箭手
A little archer
Un arquerito.
很好的一个，不是吗？
A good one, wasn't there?
Una buena, ¿no había?
切割 4.
Cutting 4.
摩托车，对吧？
Motorcycle, right?
Moto, ¿no?
这是第一次还是第二次？
Was this the first or the second?
¿Este fue el primero o el segundo?
第二，对吧？
Second, right?
Segundo, ¿no?
这是第一个。
This is the first one.
Este es el primero.
库蒂想要盖帽。
Cuti wants to block the shot.
Cuti quiere bloquear el tiro.
不，但是这个很好。
No, but this one is good.
No, pero este es bien.
你可以多做一点。
You could do a little more.
Podías hacer un poquito más.
以及世界杯的第一枪。
And the first shot of the World Cup.
Y el primer tiro del Mundial.
天气很冷，不是吗？
It was cold, wasn't it?
Estaba frío, ¿no?
这让我冷了，第一枪让我冷了。
It made me cold, the first shot made me cold.
Me daba frío, me daba frío el primer tiro.
棍子在我身上摩擦。
The stick rubs against me.
Me roza el palo.
我本来可以多做一点。
I could have done a little more.
Podría haber hecho un poquito más.
不，但是球也飞了很多。
No, but the ball flew a lot too.
No, pero la pelota volaba mucho también.
他们对你打进的第二个进球也是如此。
The second goal they score against you too.
El segundo gol que te hacen también.
是的，但是投资是多少。
Yes, but how invested it was.
Sí, pero que invertido estaba.
之后我又踢了一脚，他们把我放了进去。
After this I kicked one more and they put me in.
Después de este me pateé una más y me metían.
我不记得了。
I don't remember.
No me acuerdo.
第一个？
The first?
¿El primero?
不管怎样，钩住并拉动罗索纳。
Hook and pull the rosona anyway.
Engancha y tira igual la rosona.
皮肤接触它，我接触它，它接触棍子并进入。
The skin touches it, I touch it and it touches the stick and enters.
La toca el cuti, la rozo yo y roza el palo y entra.
他是悄无声息的来的吧？
He came silently, right?
Vino mudo, ¿no?
¡呃？
¿Eh?
他是悄无声息的来的吧？
He came silently, right?
Vino mudo, ¿no?
是的，一切都……是在银行里还是什么？
Yes, everything is... Is it in the bank or what?
Sí, todo está… ¿Está en el banco o qué?
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不，但这件事对我影响不大。
No, but this one didn't affect me much.
No, pero este no me afectó mucho.
另一位，对吗？
The other one, right?
El otro, ¿no?
这是一对一的，什么也没有发生。
This is one on one, nothing happens.
Este es un a uno, no pasa nada.
另一件事对我的影响更大一些。
The other one affected me a little more.
El otro me afectó un poco más.
一桶冷水。
A bucket of cold water.
Un bal de agua fría.
就像墨西哥一样，事实令人难以置信。
Just like Mexico, the truth is incredible.
Igual a México, la verdad es increíble.
有点糟糕，对吧？
A little bad, right?
Un poquito malo, ¿no?
有点不好。
A little bad.
Un poquito malo.
太明显了。
It was so obvious.
Estaba re obvio.
你将离开会议厅。
You are going to leave the chamber.
Vas a salir de la cámara.
真的，真的。
Really, really.
De verdad, de verdad.
这是一个伟大的目标，朋友。
It was a great goal, friend.
Fue un golazo, amigo.
谢谢我的朋友。
Thanks my friend.
Gracias, amigo.
这是一个伟大的目标。
It was a great goal.
Fue un golazo.
是的，除此之外我们还在那里受苦。
Yes, apart from that we were suffering there.
Sí, aparte estábamos sufriendo ahí.
和？
And?
¿Y qué?
我们会1-0吗？
Are we going 1-0?
¿Vamos 1-0?
是的，但是有了这个小目标......
Yes, but with that little goal already...
Sí, pero con ese golcito ya...
这个进球差点让我哭了。
That goal almost made me cry.
Casi me hago llorar en ese gol.
文字。
Literal.
而且，你在世界杯之前的友谊赛之前就已经尝试过一次了。
Besides, you had already tried one before the friendly before the World Cup.
Aparte bien, ya habías intentado uno antes del amistoso ante del Mundial.
他跟谁打了棍子，对吗？
Who did he hit the stick with, right?
Con quien pegó en el palo, ¿no?
是洪都拉斯吗？
Was it with Honduras?
¿Con Honduras fue?
看到的人，你用梳子打他，40米。
The person who sees, you hit him with the comb and 40 meters.
La persona que ve, le pegaste con el peina y 40 metros.
但他已经走得很远了，愚蠢的。
But he went far, stupid.
Pero fue re lejos, boludo.
多么可怕啊！
How terrible!
¡Qué terrible!
有多少玩具？
How many toys?
¿Cuántos juguetes?
这只是一场友谊赛吗？
Was it just a friendly match?
¿Un partido amistoso fue nomás?
的？
Of the?
¿Dos?
那么，一。
One, then.
Uno, pues.
嗯，实际上另一个也进来了，是的。
Well, actually the other one came in too, yes.
Va, en realidad el otro entré también, sí.
你是否也像这位朋友想象的那样呢？
Did you imagine it like this friend?
¿Te lo imaginabas amigo así?
我什至没有想象去，想象一下。
I didn't even imagine going, imagine.
Ni imaginaba ir, imaginate.
那儿呢？
And there?
¿Y ahí?
它已经在那里了。
There it already was.
Ahí ya fue.
但是你带自行车了吗？
But did you bring a bicycle?
¿Pero metiste bicicletita?
拴住
hitch
enganche
他开始疯狂地举重，不是吗？
He started lifting like crazy, didn't he?
Empezó a levantar como loco, ¿no?
他开始站起来，英塔就像疯了一样，人们……
He started to get up, Inta was like crazy, the people...
Empezó a levantar, el Inta era como loco, la gente...
他开始像其他人一样把我举起来。
He started to lift me up like another.
Me empezó a levantar como en otra.
我受伤了，朋友。
I get hurt, friend.
Me laso, amigo.
那里是红色的。
red there.
colorado ahí.
那天对我来说真的很热。
It was really hot for me that day.
A mí un re calor hacia ese día.
是的，除此之外，那是最糟糕的领域，对吧？
Yes, on top of that that was the worst field, right?
Sí, encima esa fue la peor cancha, ¿no?
与鞋跟。
With the heel.
Con el talón.
¡我可真是！
¡Me quemé!
这就是为什么我把它扔给那个奇怪的农民。
That's why I threw it at the weird farmer.
Por eso te lo tiré a la rara alquero.
他做得很好，因为有时候……发生的事情是他听教练的话，教练说的，对吗？
He does well, because sometimes... What happens is that he listened to the coach, the coach said, right?
Le va bien, porque a veces... Lo que pasa es que escuchó al entrenador, el entrenador dijo, ¿no?
朋友，我发誓，当你进球的时候，他说斯卡罗尼在中场休息时说过这句话。
Friend, I swear that when you scored the goal he said that Scaloni said this at halftime.
Amigo, te juro que cuando metiste el gol dijo que esto lo dijo Scaloni en entretiempo.
碰巧与此同时，他说辩方……
And it happens that in the meantime he had said that the defense...
Y pasa que entre tiempo había dicho que la defensa...
马蒂·马纳斯也把它授予了他，是吗？
And Mati Manas awarded it to him too, eh?
Y Mati Manas se lo adjudicó también, ¿eh?
一点。
A bit.
Un poquito.
不，但是莫利说……你看到了吗，他总是向边路、右后卫射门，因为他踢球……
No, but Moli said... Did you see that he always shoots at the sides, the right back, because he played...
No, pero dijo Moli... Viste que siempre le tira a los laterales, el lateral derecho, porque jugó...
爱，抬起头，射向中后卫，这将是必胜的进球。
Love, raise your head and shoot to the center back, it will be the sure goal.
Amor, levanta la cabeza y tira al centro atrás, que va a ser el gol seguro.
我们看到他们在里面走了很多路，他告诉我要受到惩罚，要受到惩罚。
We had seen that they went a lot inside and he told me to get to the point of punishment, to get to the point of punishment.
Habíamos visto que se metían mucho adentro y me decía llegar al punto de penada, llegar al punto de penada.
你可以看到它。
You can see it.
Puede verlo.
1-0还是2-0？
1-0 or 2-0?
¿El 1-0 o el 2-0?
不，1-0。
No, 1-0.
下半场才刚刚开始。
The second half had barely started.
A penas arrancó segundo tiempo.
朱利安打进第二球。
Julián scored the second.
El segundo lo metió Julián.
这是一个触摸带。
It's a touch band.
Es una banda de toque.
你在那场比赛中进行了单挑。
You had a heads-up in that match.
Tuviste un mano-a-mano en ese partido.
那场比赛我们打得很好。
In that game we played well.
En ese partido jugamos bien.
这是我们发挥最好的一组。
It is the group that we play best.
Es el grupo el que mejor jugamos.
上半场我们踢得很好。
In the first half we played well.
En primer tiempo jugamos bien.
世界杯的第一个进球，是和家人一起打进的。
First goal in a World Cup, there with the family.
Primer gol en un Mundial, ahí con la familia.
所以，你开始了，我们开始赢了，你是什么意思？
So, you started, we started to win, what do you mean?
O sea, que arrancaste vos, empezamos a ganar, ¿qué querés decir?
令人印象深刻。
It's impressive.
Está impresionante.
这是啥，罚单？
What is this, a penalty?
¿Esto qué es, un penal?
我知道，我有……
I know it, I have it...
Ya la sé, la tengo...
如果什么！
What if!
¡Andai!
荷兰第一！
Holland, the first!
¡Holanda, el primero!
你知道我们从那里开始！
You knew we were starting there!
¡Sabías que partíamos ahí!
哈诺里亚斯·马丁内斯！
Hanorías Martínez!
¡Hanorías Martínez!
我在足总杯决赛对阵切尔西的比赛中看到了范迪克。
I saw Van Dijk in the FA Cup final against Chelsea.
Yo lo vi a Van Dijk en la final del FA Cup contra el Chelsea.
奎帕留在那里，然后他把它给了，移动并扔在那里。
That Quepa stayed there and then he gave it, moved and threw it there anyway.
Que Quepa se le quedó ahí y luego lo dio, se movió y se la tiró igual ahí.
我的意思是，世界杯在那里必须表现强劲。
I mean, the World Cup has to go strong there.
Digo, el Mundial tiene que ir fuerte ahí.
但是，朋友们，你们知道，这次处罚之后我腰痛了一年。
But, friends, you know that after this penalty I had a year of waist pain.
Pero, amigos, sabés que después de este penal tuve un año con dolor de cintura.
当我把腰放在这边时，它发出“pac，man！”的声音。
When I dropped my waist on this side, it went “pac, man!”
Cuando caí la cintura de este lado, me hizo ¡pac, amigo!
朋友，你对他说了些什么吗？
Did you say something to him, friend?
¿Le dijiste algo, amigo?
不不。
No no.
No, no.
你们没谈过吗？
Didn't you talk about it?
¿No lo hablaste?
不，不，因为我知道那家伙非常专业。
No, no, because I knew that the guy is very professional.
No, no, porque sabía que el chabón es re profesional.
你等我一会儿了吗？
Did you wait for me a little?
¿Me esperaste un poquito?
不不。
No no.
No, no.
哦真的吗？
Oh really?
¿En serio?
我什至没有看你一眼。
I didn't even look at you.
Ni te miraba.
他甚至没有看我一眼。
He didn't even look at me.
Ni me miraba.
就等……不，但他踢得很用力。
Just wait until... No, but he kicks very hard.
Esperate igual a que... No, pero patea muy fuerte.
他踢得很用力，而且总是有一个。
He kicks very hard and there is always one.
Patea muy fuerte y siempre ahí uno.
我等着这个，我吃它......
I wait for this one, I eat it...
Yo espero a este, me la como...
不不。
No no.
No, no.
但你说那是最难的，对吧​​？
But that was the hardest, you said, right?
Pero ese fue el más difícil, dijiste, ¿no?
是的，这个确实如此。
Yes, this one does.
Sí, este sí.
在阻止世界杯的处罚中，这一点是关键。
Of the penalties to stop the World Cup, this one was key.
De los penales de atajar el Mundial, este era clave.
比赛中的第一个球员做出了一次糟糕的扑救。
The first in the game had made a bad save.
El primero en el partido había atajado mal.
他们也来过两次。
They have arrived twice as well.
Me han llegado dos veces también.
最重要的是，这是我们制作的第一批，对吧？
On top of that, it was the first batch we made, right?
Encima era la primera tanda que hacíamos, ¿no?
波格在世界杯首轮。
The first round of Pog, in the World Cup.
La primera tanda de Pog, en el Mundial.
第一次切花并没有给我任何定义花束的机会
And the first chopping gave me nothing to define the bouquet
Y el tajar primero no me dio nada para definir el ramo
而你在对阵荷兰的比赛中没有听我的。
And you didn't listen to me against Holland.
Y no me escuchaste contra Holanda.
前一天我说……中间，他说。
The day before I said... In the middle, he said.
El día anterior decí... Al medio, dijo.
伙计，你的头碰在横梁上是真的。
Dude, it's real to touch your head on a crossbar.
Amigo, es real tocarle la cabeza a un travesaño.
是的，我前一天就告诉过你了。
Yes, I told you the day before.
Sí, te dije el día anterior.
如果你存一个……你还记得中踢训练吗？
If you save one... Do you remember the middle kick training?
Si atajas uno... ¿Te acuerdas del entrenamiento de patear medio?
你踢对了吗？
And did you kick it right?
¿Y lo pateaste bien?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我说，啊，就是这样。
And I said, ah, that's it.
Y dije, ah, ya fue eso.
当然，因为这是你的错，所以他们又给了我一个处罚。
Of course, because it's your fault they gave me one more penalty.
Claro, porque culpa tuya me metieron un penal más.
统计数据，统计数据。
The statistics, the statistics.
La estadística, la estadística.
下来吧，朋友。
Come down, friend.
Baje, amigo.
看看统计数据。
Look at the statistics.
Mira la estadística.
这就是我的统计数据下降的地方。
That's where the statistics went down for me.
Ahí me bajó la estadística.
就是为了让他有点兴奋。
It was to give him a little excitement.
Era para darle un poco de emoción.
来自公牛的那一位即将到来。
The one from the Bull is coming.
Viene la del Toro.
如果公牛撞到你怎么办？
What if the Bull crashes into you?
¿Y si te estrella el Toro?
他告诉你什么了？
What was he telling you?
¿Qué te decía?
你都明白了吗？
Did you understand everything?
¿Todo lo entendía?
我根本不明白。
I didn't understand it at all.
No lo entendía nada.
我完全不明白，但是...
I don't understand it at all, but...
No lo entiendo nada, pero...
已经在球场中央了，你看到他们开始咬人了。
Already in the middle of the court, you saw that they were starting to bite.
Ya de la mitad de la cancha, viste que empezaban a picar.
我也是，我是那里银行的守门员。
Me too, I am the goalkeeper of the banks there.
Yo también, yo soy el arquero de los bancos ahí.
但你必须了解游戏的厨房。
But you have to know the kitchen of the game.
Pero tiene que saber la cocina del juego.
不，碰巧我正在看着你。
No, it happens that I was looking at you.
No, pasa que te miraba vos.
阿根廷糖果所做的，我们也会做。
What Argentine candy does, we are going to do the same.
El caramelo argentino lo que hace, vamos a hacer lo mismo.
这就是撤回吧？
This is the withdrawal, right?
Este es el retirabante, ¿no?
是的，但他也很大。
Yes, but he was big too.
Sí, pero estaba re grandote también.
我一看，有这么一个判罚，我们就站在一起了。
When I saw it, there was such a penalty and we stood next to each other.
Yo cuando lo vi, va tanta penal y nos paramos uno al lado del otro.
朋友们，他用骚乱给了我两米，我就这样看着他，愚蠢的。
Friends, he gave me two meters with riots and I looked at him like that, stupid.
Amigos, yo con motines me dio dos metros y yo lo miraba así, boludo.
我一脚踢开 我一脚踢开
I kicked open I kicked open
Yo pateaba abierto Yo pateaba abierto
然后我停了下来，看到他移动了一点。
And then I stopped and I saw him move a little.
Y después me frené y lo vi que se movió un poquito.
但他很久以前就没有告诉过我。
But he didn't even tell me that long ago.
Pero no hace ni que me dijo.
你过得很愉快，呵呵。
You had a good time, huh.
Buen hopo tenías, eh.
谢天谢地我改变了。
Thank goodness I changed.
Menos mal que cambié.
你没有告诉我任何关于...什么都没有，你看起来很好，白痴。
You didn't tell me anything about... Nothing, it looked good on you, idiot.
No me decías nada de... Nada, te quedaba bien, boludo.
它适合你吗？
Did it fit you well?
¿Te quedaba bien?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你也把我的这一点夺走了，一个小丑，一个白痴。
You take that away from me too, a clown, idiot.
Yo me llevas eso también, un payaso, boludo.
啊，庆祝活动。
Ah, the celebration.
Ah, el festejo.
我以为是那个取消我的人。
I thought it was the one who had canceled me.
Pensé que era el que me habían anulado.
他们大约有 6 个进球被判无效。
They disallowed about 6 goals.
Me anularon como 6 goles.
即使在训练中，我也不允许进球。
Even in training, goals were disallowed for me.
Hasta en los entrenamientos me anulaban goles.
事实上，我在那里降低了你的级别，你是一个伟大的进球，但我希望你能去右边庆祝。
The truth is that I downgraded you there, you were a great goal, but I expected you to go and celebrate it on the right side.
Yo la verdad ahí te rebanqué, fuiste un golazo, pero yo esperaba que vayas a festejarlo para el lado derecho.
我还以为我要跑回来呢？
And I thought I was going to run back?
¿Y yo pensé que me iba a correr atrás?
不，我失败了，多米。
No, I fell flat, Domi.
No, yo caí palma, Domi.
曾是...
Was...
Estaba...
我浑身发抖。
I was shaking.
Estaba temblando.
然后。
Then.
En ese momento.
情感。
The emotion.
La emoción.
除此之外，情况很糟糕。
Besides it was bad.
Aparte que estaba mal.
而且脚踝还漂浮着。
And the ankle was floating.
Y el tobillo flotaba.
当我在理疗师看到你的脚踝被注射时，那场比赛是哪场比赛？
What was that game when I saw you in the physio suffering from having your ankle injected?
¿Cuál fue ese partido que te vi en el fisio sufriendo que te estaban inyectando el tobillo?
是这个吗？
Was it this?
¿Era este?
¡波兰？
¿O Poland?
¿O Polonia?
他们正在给你的脚踝重新注射。
They were re-injecting your ankle.
Te estaban re-injectando el tobillo.
继波兰之后。
After Poland.
Después de Polonia.
在波兰之后，在完成了为期六天的小组赛后，我被困在那里。
After Poland, after finishing the groups, which we had six days, I got stuck there.
Después de Polonia, después de terminar los grupos, que teníamos seis días, me clavé ahí.
洪比达
the hombida
la hombida
这个进球后我杀了他。
I killed him after this goal.
Yo lo maté después de este gol.
他们带她前进。
They take her forward.
La llevan para adelante.
我告诉阿拉尼亚，愚蠢，但我把它放在某人身上了吗？
I told Araña, stupid, but did I put it in someone?
Le dije a Araña, boludo, pero ¿la metí a alguien?
我告诉他，朋友...
I told him, friend...
Le dije, amigo...
让我们看看他是如何反对的。
Let's see how he came out against it.
A ver cómo salió del contra.
还有莫莉。
And Moli too.
Y Moli también.
跑得最出色的是莫利诺。
The one who ran impressively was Molino.
El que corrió impresionante fue Molino.
啊，但在那之前他已经留下了短篇。
Ah, but before that he had left the short.
Ah, pero antes había salido de la corta.
然后他施加压力，它反弹，然后我们清除它。
Then he put pressure, it rebounded, then we cleared it.
Después presionó, le rebotó, después la despejamos.
我带着它，看到了吗？
I carried it, see?
Yo lo cargué, ¿viste?
我喜欢带着它。
I like to carry it.
Me gusta cargarlo.
蜘蛛一切都很好，事实是你跑了，你防守了，你压迫了，但你走了某人。
Everything was fine with the spider, the truth is you ran, you defended, you pressed, but you walked someone.
La araña todo bien, la verdad corriste, defendiste, presionaste, pero caminaste a alguien.
我能做到，我是弓箭手。
I can do that, I'm an archer.
Eso lo puedo hacer yo, que soy arquero.
监狱？
The prison?
¿El penal?
是的，这就是惩罚，朋友。
Yes, it was the penalty, friend.
Sí, fue el penal, amigo.
这是惩罚。
It was the penalty.
Fue el penal.
如果他们在合同中向你收费...有时他们每次都会向我收费。
If they charge you in contract... And they charge me each time sometimes.
Si te lo cobran en contracto… Y me cobran cada una a veces.
该死！
Damn!
¡Caraña!
不，我是最……我不了解你，是的。
No, I'm the one who most... I don't know about you, yeah.
No, yo el que más... No sé ustedes, sí.
因为他总是告诉我……不是有那张照片吗？
Because he always told me... Isn't there a photo of that one?
Porque a mí siempre me decía... ¿No está la foto de esa?
那？
That?
¿Qué?
生气还是什么？
Angry or what?
¿Enojado o qué?
一个不知道衬衫的人。
The one who doesn't know about the shirt.
La que no sabe de la remera.
我想打人。
I wanted to hit someone.
Le quería pegar a alguien.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!
不，但我喘得很厉害，朋友。
No, but I was gasping a lot, friend.
No, pero boqueaba mucho, amigo.
我将屏幕截图发送给了 Tokali。
I sent a screenshot to Tokali.
Yo le mandé una captura a Tokali.
凌晨两点。
at two in the morning.
a las dos de la mañana.
我总是和那里的胖子打交道。
I always deal with the fat guy there.
Yo me trato siempre con el gordo de ahí.
我看到，好吧，如果我们进入点球大战我们就会获胜，我们已经研究过这一点，上次他们在点球大战中输给荷兰队时。
and I saw that, well, if we go to penalties we win, we have already studied it, the last time they had lost to Holland on penalties.
y vi que, bueno, si vamos a penales ganamos, ya lo tenemos estudiado, la última vez habían perdido con Holanda en el penales.
我们赢了。
We win.
Se ganamos.
我把它拍下来并发送给他玩。
I captured it and sent it to him to play.
Hice captura y se la mandó a tocar.
2014年，不？
2014, ¿no?
我在玩火。
I was playing with fire.
Estaba jugando con fuego.
我已经告诉过你了。
I had told you.
Te lo había dicho.
再说了，他以前也喘过气，他喘过气，安杰利托对他不好，你看，他没有告诉安杰利托这个故事。
Besides, he had gasped before, he had gasped, Angelito had treated him badly, you see, he had not told Angelito the story.
aparte había boqueado antes, había boqueado, Angelito lo había tratado mal, viste, no me había contado a Angelito la historia
我的电缆交叉了。
And my cable got crossed.
Y se me se cruzó lo cable.
但你却让它复活了。
But there you revived it.
Pero ahí se lo reviviste.
对我来说，他是最来自克罗地亚的球员，当你进入半决赛时，你会告诉他你已经参加了全部七场比赛。
He is the one who most, for me, the one from Croatia, when you go to the semi-final you tell him that you have already been in all seven games.
Es el que más, para mí, el de Croacia, cuando vos pasas a la semifinal le dices que ya fuiste en los siete partidos.
不是情绪化，而是抑郁。
Not as emotional, but as depression.
No como emotivo, sino como depresión.
是的，因为他剪得不好。
Yes, because he wasn't cutting well.
Sí, porque no venía tajando bien.
我感觉自己做得不太好。
I didn't feel like I was doing well.
Yo no me sentía que venía tajando bien.
墨西哥并没有给我太多帮助，阿拉伯和荷兰对我进了两个球。
Mexico didn't get me much, Arabia and Holland had scored two goals against me.
México no me llegaron mucho, Arabia y Holanda me habían tirado dos goles.
这给了我...把它坚持到最后，对吗？
And this gave me... Getting it to the end, right?
Y esto me dio... Sacándole a final, ¿no?
但对我来说，他们打平了我们，那是最……
But for me too, they tied us and that was the game that most...
Pero para mí también, que nos empataron y eso fue el partido que más...
对我来说，来自墨西哥的，对吗？
For me, the one from Mexico, right?
Para mí, el de México, ¿no?
朋友，来自荷兰的那个很糟糕。
The one from Holland, friend, was terrible.
El de Holanda, amigo, fue terrible.
对我来说，墨西哥的情况是埃多球门的情况。
That of Mexico, for me, the situation of the Edo goal.
El de México, para mí, la situación del gol del Edo.
它引起了我的注意。
It catches my attention.
Me llama la atención.
看看Leo的进球情况，那就是我们爆发的地方。
Look at the situation with Leo's goal, that's where we exploded.
Mira la situación del gol de Leo, ahí explotamos.
我在墨西哥队的比赛中，我的胃很痛。
I was on the field with Mexico and my stomach hurt.
Yo con México estaba dentro de la cancha y me dolía la panza.
但在荷兰队，当他们打平我们时，我并不紧张，就像在墨西哥一样。
But with Holland, when they tied us, I wasn't nervous, like in Mexico.
pero yo con Holanda, cuando nos empatan, no estaba nervioso, como en México.
当他们不打领带的时候，对吧？
When they don't tie, right?
Cuando no empatan, ¿no?
不，朋友，我不像墨西哥之前那么紧张。
No, friend, I wasn't as nervous as I was before Mexico.
No, amigo, no estaba tan nervioso como antes de México.
对我来说，领带太糟糕了。
For me the tie was terrible.
Para mí el empate fue terrible.
我躺在栅栏上面，在栅栏下面。
I was lying on top, below the barrier.
Yo estaba encima tirado, abajo de la barrera.
我看到那幅画在移动，再见，我说。
and I see the drawing that moves, bye, I said.
y lo veo al Dibu que se mueve, chau, dije.
我正在看戏，我说……
I'm looking at the play and I say...
Yo estoy mirando la jugada y digo...
我对罚球并不感到惊讶。
I wasn't surprised by the free throw.
No me sorprendió el tiro libre.
我说，我会把自己摆在这里，他不会把我摆在我的位置上。
I said, I'll put myself here, he won't put me in my position.
Yo dije, me pongo acá, en mi palo no me mete.
距离如此之近，朋友。
It was so close, friend.
Estaba re cerca, amigo.
他将手臂放在我身边。
He put his arm along my side.
Me puso el brazo a lo largo.
我先到了球。
I got to the ball first.
Yo llegué a la pelota primero.
但你打了他……当我想去那里时，他们把胳膊放在我身上。
But you hit him... When I want to get there, they put their arm on me.
Pero vos le pegaste... Cuando yo quiero llegar, me ponen el brazo.
我向后倒在空中并踢了那里。
And I fell back in the air and kicked there.
Y yo en el aire me caí para atrás y ahí pateé.
你的错误是试图清除它。
Your mistake was trying to clear it.
Tu error fue tratar de despejarla.
他必须挡住投篮。
He must block the shot.
Debe bloquear el tiro.
当然，我想把事情弄清楚。
Of course, I wanted to clear it up.
Claro, yo quería despejarlo.
当你打他时，你抓伤他，他就会这么做。
When you hit him, you scratch him, and he does that.
Cuando vos le pegás, vos le ras, y él hace así.
如果我试图阻止，我就会阻止它，但我想把它弄出来。
If I tried to block, I blocked it, but I wanted to get it out.
Si intentaba bloquear, lo bloqueaba, pero quise sacarlo.
但当我们说我们有机会赢得冠军时，荷兰队之后的那场比赛对我来说是最重要的。
but the one after Holland was for me when we said we have a chance to win it.
pero el después de Holanda fue el para mí cuando dijimos tenemos chance de ganarla.
那是骑马的，朋友。
That was the mounted one, friend.
Ese era el montado, amigo.
这就是用来击打棍棒的东西，对吗？
That was what there was to hit the sticks with, right?
Ese fue lo que hubo para tirar a los palos, ¿no?
我的一根棍子。
A stick of mine.
Un palo mío.
伊班代用他的脸从我身上夺走了一个。
Ibanday took one out of me with his face.
A mí Ibanday me sacó una con la cara.
然后我们参加了安杰利托的几届奥运会。
Then we had a couple of Olympics from Angelito.
Después tuvimos un par de olímpicos de Angelito.
然后你击中了禁区外的一球。
Then you hit one outside the area.
Luego le pegaste uno fuera del área.
也是左撇子。
Left-handed too.
De Zurda también.
你必须做什么？
What do you have to do?
¿Qué tenés que hacer?
你拿什么？
What do you take?
¿Qué te llevas?
法国。
France.
Francia.
好的那个。
The fine one.
La fina.
El Portiaso，在那里玩得很好。
El portiaso, play nice there.
El portiaso, jugate bonito ahí.
朋友给我这个图。
Friend for me the figure.
Amigo para mí la figura.
我已经让你成为了党内的人物。
And I already made you a figure of the party.
Y ya te hice una figura del partido.
对我来说，是的，这是我玩过的最好的游戏。
For me, yes, it was the best game I played.
Para mí sí, fue el mejor partido que jugué.
可以说，通过选择。
with the selection, let's say.
con la selección, digamos.
对我来说，我最喜欢你决赛的不是传球之类的。
For me, what I liked most about your final was not the pass or that.
Para mí, la que más me gustó de la final tuya no fue el pase ni eso.
我很喜欢这样的比赛，在一场比赛中我们以 2-0 获胜。
I liked it, in one we were winning 2-0.
Me gustó, en una íbamos ganando 2-0.
他没有去角落，对吧？
He didn't go for the corner, right?
No fue a tener el córner, ¿no?
你有玉米饼、塔基托，你给了我信心，我说我们有多好。
You have corne, taquito and you gave me confidence and I said how good we were.
tenés corne, taquito y me diste una confianza y dije que bien que estabamos.
我变大了。
I got bigger.
Me agrandé yo.
那一刻我们已经有了很大的信心，我们2-0了。
And at that moment there was already a lot of confidence, we were 2-0.
Y ya en ese momento ya había mucha confianza, íbamos 2-0.
我们正在杀死它，那场比赛是我最喜欢的。
We were killing it, that game I enjoyed the most.
Lo estábamos matando, ese partido que más disfruté.
直到70岁。
Until 70.
Hasta los 70.
那是什么，75？
What was it, 75?
¿Qué fue, 75?
32、我想另一种……我稍后会选择另一种，我不同意吗？
32, I think another... I'll choose another one later, don't I agree?
32, creo que otra... Yo después elige a otra, ¿no acuerdo?
??太田？
¿Ota?
我的意思是，你为什么不把它留给我手牵手，对角线？
I mean, why didn't you leave it to me hand in hand, diagonally?
Digo, ¿por qué no me lo dejaste mano a mano, en diagonal?
他说，不，我想跳，你明白吗？
He says, no, I wanted to jump, you see?
Dice, no, que yo quise saltar, ¿viste?
但我很享受我的比赛。
But I was enjoying my game.
Pero yo venía disfrutando del partido mío.
如果再加上一项，那就和克罗地亚一样了。
If we add one more, it was the same as Croatia.
Si le metemos uno más, era igual que Croatia.
我们在这里打得很好，直到我们 70 岁。那场比赛......
Here we played very well until we were 70. That game was...
Aquí jugamos muy bien hasta los 70 Ese partido fue...
你打算放一个70分钟的盒子吗？
Are you going to put a 70 minute box?
¿Va a poner un cuadrito de 70 minutos?
为了我或你或...
For me or you or...
Para mí o vos o...
谁进球了？
Who played goal?
¿Quién jugó de goleo?
这也是，朋友。
That too, friend.
Eso también, amigo.
不，但是上面的每个人都在玩。
No, but everyone above plays.
No, pero todos los de arriba juegan.
不，安杰利托，朋友。
No, Angelito, friend.
No, Angelito, amigo.
很一般，球队...
It was general, the team was...
Fue general, el equipo estaba...
他们强调了一切。
They highlighted everything.
Resaltaron todo.
右边的小天使杀了他。
Little right side angel killed him.
Angelito lateral derecho lo mató.
小心点，总有一天任何事情都可能发生。
Be careful, anything can happen someday.
Cuidado, puede salir cualquier cosa algún día.
没人打篮球吧？
There isn't one playing basketball, right?
¿No hay una jugando al básquet, no?
都在一起吧？
All together, right?
Todos juntos, ¿no?
好吧，去篮球吧。
Well, to basketball.
Bueno, al básquet.
我们打篮球，你也打篮球，一切都受伤了。
We played basketball, well you were, everything hurt.
Jugamos al básquet, bueno fuiste, te dolía todo.
一切都坏了，对吧？
Everything broken, right?
Todo roto, ¿no?
不，朋友们，我们在荷兰队之前在那里踢过球。
No, friends, we played there before Holland.
No, amigos, ahí jugamos antes de Holanda.
晚上12点我们打篮球比赛。
We play a basketball game at 12 at night.
jugamos partido de básquet a las 12 de la noche.
现在我们可以这么说了，对吧，托罗？
Now we can say it, right, Toro?
Ahora lo podemos decir, ¿no, Toro?
我不会去纹身。
I wouldn't get it tattooed.
Yo no me lo tatuaría.
晚上12点？
12 at night?
¿Las 12 de la noche?
托罗，我希望我们在最后一扇门前打篮球。
Toro, I want us to play basketball before the final doors.
Toro, quiero que juguemos al básquet antes de las puertas de final.
当时是晚上11点、12点。
It was 11, 12 at night.
Era 11, 12 de la noche.
结果就这样结束了，对吧？
And it ended as for one, right?
Y terminó como para uno, ¿no?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
但我要离开这里吗？
But am I leaving here?
¿Pero ando de aquí?
从后面。
From behind.
De atrás.
一家人去的那个巨大的泳池怎么样？
How about the giant pool where the family went?
¿Qué tal la pileta gigante donde iba la familia?
或者是分钟，对我来说就是分钟。
Or the minute, for me it is the minute.
O el minuto, para mí es el minuto.
不就是为了给你拍照吗？
Not to take your photo, right?
Para no hacerte la foto, ¿no?
关于什么？
About what?
¿De qué?
来自J.巴斯克斯？
¿From J. Basquez?
¿De J.Basquez?
我没有意识到。
I didn't realize it.
Yo no me di cuenta.
是这个的吗？
Of this one?
¿De esta?
我给你蒙上了一层阴影。
I had clouded you.
Yo te había nublado.
是的，我又给你蒙上了一层阴影，朋友。
Yes, I had clouded you another one, friend.
Sí, yo te había nublado otra, amigo.
这就是惩罚。
That was the penalty.
Ahí fue el penal.
但处罚，当然是罚球，已经发生了。
But the penalty, box of course, had already happened.
Pero el penal, caja claro, ya había pasado.
卡奇罚的是什么？
What was the cachi putting the penalty.
Lo que era el cachi poniendo el penal.
不，朋友，这个……同样，朋友。
No, friend, this... Same, friend.
No, amigo, esta... Igual, amigo.
兄弟，还剩一分钟。
Dude, one minute left.
Amigo, falta un minuto.
这是他们的手，以前的。
It is their hand, previous.
Es mano de ellos, anterior.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
但是，兄弟，当然，朋友，它来自科纳特。
But, brother, of course, friend, it's from Conaté.
Pero, hermano, claro, amigo, es de Conaté.
但他对他做了这样的事吗？
But did he do that to him?
Pero, ¿le hizo así?
他这样做了，然后走到外面，打到了纸上，打到了你。
He does this and then goes outside and hits the paper and hits you.
Hace así y después sale afuera y le pega en papel y te pega a vos.
但你没看过之前的剧吗？
But you didn't see the previous play?
¿Pero vos no viste la jugada anterior?
角落？
The corner?
¿El corner?
我看到了视频，但我不知道是不是……我不知道视频是不是假的，我不知道。
I saw the video, but I don't know if... I don't know if the video is fake, I don't know.
Yo vi el video, pero no sé si... No sé si es trucho el video, no sé.
非常好。
It's very good.
Es buenísimo.
谁为你启动？
Who starts it for you?
¿Quién te lo inicia?
就是这样，我会告诉你50遍。
That's it, I'll tell you 50 times.
Ya está, 50 veces la te digo.
他疯狂地偷窃。
He's stealing like crazy.
Está robando como loco.
它已被盗。
It has been stolen.
Se ha robado.
你要发明什么？
What are you going to invent?
¿Qué vas a inventar?
前几天有时我会感到小腿疼痛。
Sometimes the other day I had calf pain.
A veces el otro día tenía dolor de gemelo.
我把那根棍子留给了他，他说。
That I left him that stick, he said.
Que le dejé ese palo, dijo.
他和利物浦一起倒下了。
And he went down with Liverpool.
Y bajó con el Liverpool.
队医来了，他已经像往常一样乱搞了，在比赛前他让他的小腿发怒了。
and the Physio comes, already messing around as always, and he had his calf in a rage before the game against this.
y viene el Fisio, ya boludeando como siempre, y tenía el gemelo arremal antes del partido contra esto.
我告诉你，不，朋友，这条腿很重。
And I tell you, no friends, this leg weighs a lot.
Y aparte le digo, no amigos, aparte pesa un montón esta pierna.
我听不懂英语中的鱼。
I didn't understand fish in English.
No entendí el fish en inglés.
用英语，对吧？
In English, right?
En inglés, ¿no?
就是为了这个。
It was for this one.
Era por esta.
但多么疯狂啊。
But how crazy.
Pero qué locura.
我坐在他们把我换下的替补席上，朋友，我发誓，替补席上没有人做出反应，白痴。
I was on the bench where they had taken me out, friend, and I swear, no one on the substitute bench reacted, idiot.
Yo estaba en el banco que me habían sacado, amigo, y te juro, en el banco suplente no reaccionó nadie, boludo.
就好像他们都震惊了。
It was like they were all in shock.
Era como que estaban todos en shock.
这完全在该领域内。
That's well inside the field.
Eso está bien adentro de la cancha.
我意识到这太棒了。
I realized it was great.
Me di cuenta que fue grande.
我发誓我保存了很多比俱乐部更好的球。
I swear that I have saved many better balls than the club.
Te juro que yo he atajado muchas mejores pelotas que el club.
它击中了你哪里？
Where does it hit you?
¿Dónde te pega?
就在这里，朋友。
Right here, friend.
Justo acá, amigo.
是的，我发誓。
Yes, I swear.
Sí, te juro.
我的意思是技术意义上的，但有一个转折。
I meant it in the technical sense, but there is a twist.
Lo decía en el sentido técnico, pero hay una tajada.
我们在基督里跳舞。
That we dance in Christ.
Que bailamos en Cristo.
在这一次我说，拜托，把我的脸炸起来。
In this one I said, please, blow my face up.
Yo en esta dije, por favor, reventame la cara.
当时你在哪里？
Where were you?
¿Vos dónde estabas?
我...对我来说并非如此...因为我们就像约会一样，然后...
I was... For me it wasn't so... Because we were like dating and then came the...
Yo estaba... Para mí no era tan... Porque estábamos como saliendo y después vino el...
他们再次拒绝。
They reject again.
Ellos rechazan de nuevo.
你知道什么对我有一点帮助吗？
You know what helped me a little?
¿Sabes lo que me ayudó un poco?
其中，太田主罚了点球。
In which Ota had made the penalty.
En que Ota había hecho el penal.
那东西吃掉了前锋的背。
that had eaten the striker's back.
que le había comido la espalda al delantero.
当然，当他用T扔球时……
Of course, when he threw the ball with the T...
Claro, cuando tiró el pelotazo con la T...
我说，太田吃了，错了。
I said, Ota eats it, the mistake.
Yo dije, se lo come a Ota, el error.
太田还没有到来。
Ota does not arrive.
Ota no llega.
由于不信任防守，他让我做好准备。
And distrusting the defense, he let me be ready.
Y al desconfiar de la defensa, me dejó estar listo.
如果我相信别人会拿走它...我有时间把它扔给你。
If I trust someone else to take it... I had time to throw it over you.
Si yo confío que otra la saca... Tenía tiempo para tirártela por arriba.
不，因为他在等她。
No, because he is waiting for her.
No, porque él la está esperando.
如果我逃跑了，就像那个小家伙对埃德森所做的那样，你明白吗？
And if I run away, it's like what the little guy does to Ederson, you understand?
Y si yo salgo corriendo, es como lo que el jevito le hace a Ederson, ¿entendés?
当球落下时，你会看到他的腿会承受负荷，就像这匹击球的马一样。
And when the ball goes down, you see that he is going to load his leg, like this horse that hits it.
Y cuando la pelota va bajando, ves que va a cargar la pierna, como al caballo este que le da bombazo.
当然，我说，就是这样，我就站在他旁边，像那样对角，然后我开口了。
And of course, I said, that's it, I stood right next to him, diagonally like that, and I opened up.
Y claro, dije, ya fue, me puse derecho a él, así en diagonal, y me abrí.
也许他们给了你一点运气。
Maybe they gave you a little luck.
Igual te dieron un poquito de suerte.
是的，嗯，也在那里。
Yes, well, there too.
Sí, bueno, ahí también.
是的，你站起来一点，他们就从下面打你的小腿。
Yes, you stand up a little and they hit your calf from below.
Sí, te levantas un poquito y te pegan el gemelo por abajo.
他们进球是因为他们刺痛了我，你明白吗？
They are scoring goals because they sting me, you understand?
Me están clavando goles porque me la pican, ¿entendés?
当然，如果球落下，我的腿就会放在地板上。
Of course, if the ball is down, I have my leg on the floor.
Claro, si la pelota está abajo, yo tengo la pierna en el piso.
我没有举起它，当球击中空中时，我说，哦，好吧，我要飞得更高，你明白吗？
I didn't lift it and as the ball was hitting in the air I said, oh well, I'm going higher, you understand?
No la levanto y como la pelota estaba picando en el aire dije, va, me voy más arriba, ¿entendés?
否则，守门员通常会低下手臂。
Otherwise, normally the goalkeeper goes with his arms lowered.
Si no, normalmente el arquero va con los brazos bajos.
如果你抓住地板，你就可以在那里玩。
If you hold onto the floor, you can play there.
Si te agarras del piso, ahí sí puedes jugar.
当然，也许你把脚放下来并覆盖地板。
Sure, maybe you put your foot down and cover the floor.
Claro, capaz que bajes el pie y cubres el piso.
他要站起来了。
He's going to get up.
Se va a levantar.
他要站起来了，我的儿子。
He's going to get up, my son.
Se va a levantar, mijo.
这是不可能的。
It's not possible.
No es posible.
再说了，你连​​脸都没露出来，什么都没有。
Besides, you didn't even show your face, nothing.
Aparte, ni corriste la cara, nada.
不，我说，请把我的脸炸起来。
No, I said, please, blow my face up.
No, yo dije, por favor, reventame la cara.
嗯，通常...
Well, usually...
Pues, normalmente...
就是守门员的动作，他转身的时候，你这样做，你明白吗？
That is, the movement of the goalkeeper, when he turns, you do this, do you understand?
O sea, el movimiento del arquero, cuando gira, vos haces esto, ¿entendés?
如果它想保持这样，你就不要动。
And if it wants to stay like that, you don't move.
Y si quiere quedar así, no te mueves.
已经是了。
It was already.
Ya fue.
如果你这样做，或者你的身体这样做。
If you do this, or your body does this.
Si hacés esto, o tu cuerpo hace esto.
速度快。
At speed.
A la velocidad.
一个菜园。
A vegetable garden.
Un orto.
总结一下。
To summarize it.
A resumirlo.
你蜇我了吗？
Do you have me stung?
¿Vos me tenés picado?
我们都是蒙蒂尔！
We are all Montiel!
¡Somos todos Montiel!
那？
That?
¿Qué?
点球很可怕，但所有守门员......
The penalties are horrible, but all the goalkeepers...
Que los pastillas son horribles los penales, pero todos los arqueros...
所有的弓箭手都转向另一边。
All the archers turn to the other side.
Todos los arqueros se tiran para el otro lado.
但他为什么不找呢？
But why isn't he looking?
Pero ¿por qué no está mirando?
没有朋友，这是不可能的，一切慢慢来
No friend, it is impossible, with everything slowly
No amigo, es imposible, con todo despacito
美洲杯的那个，我记得，这一下之后，你踢同样的球，他击中了七次球，朋友。
The one from the Copa América, I remember, after this one, you kicked the same, he hit the ball seven times, friend.
El de la Copa América, yo me acuerdo, después de este, pateaste igual, le picó siete veces la pelota, amigo.
你怎么做？
How do you do it?
¿Cómo hacés?
也许在他走之前……你这样带着孩子做什么？
Maybe before he left... What are you doing like this with the baby?
Igual antes partía… ¿Qué hacés así con el bebé?
你见过伊斯雷尔·坎切罗吗？
Have you seen Israel Canchero?
¿Viste a Israel Canchero?
不，在开始谈话之前。
No, before kicking off the talk.
No, antes de patear en la charla.
但这弓箭手却有移动的倾向。
But this archer had a tendency to move.
Pero esta arquera tenía tendencia de moverse.
但因为携手发生的事情。
But because of what had happened hand in hand.
Pero por lo que había pasado de la mano.
是的，因为监狱，朋友。
Yes, because of the prison, friend.
Sí, por el penal, amigo.
这个我看哭了
I was crying this one.
Estaba llorando este.
我想象着一种享受的感觉。
I imagined a feeling of enjoyment.
Me imaginé una anda de goza.
当我们互相拥抱时，他说……
As we walked to hug each other he said...
Mientras íbamos caminando a abrazarnos decía...
看看Cache怎么样，看看Cache怎么样。
Look at how the Cache is, look at how the Cache is.
Fíjate cómo está el Cache, fíjate cómo está el Cache.
但我的朋友，如果你不为此报仇，也许……
But my friend, if you don't have revenge for this, maybe...
Pero lo que es amigo, si vos no tenés la revancha de esto, capaz que...
你还记得那个监狱吗？
Do you remember that prison all your life?
¿Te acordás de ese penal toda tu vida?
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
现在每个人都为此记住彼此。
Now everyone remembers each other for this.
Ahora todos se recuerdan por esto.
但好在你去了。
But well you went.
Pero bien vos que fuiste.
不，但事实是我感谢你所做的一切，但是抽牛奶，然后你也一样。
No, but the truth is I thank you for everything, but smoke the milk, then you too.
No, pero yo la verdad te agradezco todo, pero fuma la leche, vos luego también.
你因为骚扰而离开，没有来……是的，我不知道该怎么……我那一刻不知道该怎么办。
You left for harassment and didn't come to... Yes, I didn't know how to... I didn't know what to do at that moment.
Te fuiste de acoso y no viniste a... Sí, a mí no sabía cómo... No sabía qué hacer en ese momento.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
我先到的。
I arrived first.
Yo llegué primero.
我不知道你在做什么。
I didn't know what you were doing.
No sabía que hacías.
整个月，脱掉你的衬衫。
throughout the month and take off your shirt.
en todo el mes y sacate la remera.
多酷啊！
How cool!
¡Qué pique de chévere!
不，但是当你踢的时候，我说……
No, but when you went to kick, I said...
No, pero cuando fuiste a patear, dije...
他们都让我失望，我没有开始哭泣。
They all let me down, I didn't start crying.
Me bajaron todas, no empecé a llorar.
他们把我们都带走了...
They took us all...
Nos bajaron todos los...
当然，以这样的体质，我也脱掉了上衣。
Of course, with that physique I also take off my shirt.
Claro, con ese físico yo también me saco la camiseta.
是的，伊格纳西奥，每一天。
Yes, Ignacio, every day.
Sí, Ignacio, todos los días.
那个纹身很低。
That tattoo is very low.
Está muy bajo ese tatuaje.
我不知道该怎么办。
I didn't know what to do.
Yo no sabía qué hacer.
对我来说，当你进球时，就像你完成点球大战后跑去找他一样。
For me, when you scored the goal it was like when you finish a penalty shootout and you run to look for him.
Para mí, cuando hiciste el gol fue como cuando terminas una tanda de penales y vas corriendo a buscar a él.
在该框架内
within the framework of the
en el marco de la
而且，每个人都是一样的，你明白吗？
Besides, everyone is the same, you see?
A parte, igual todo el mundo, ¿viste?
你看到有些人和利奥一起停下来，其他人跑到银行，其他人跑到奥卡埃特。
You saw that some stopped with Leo, others ran to the bank, others ran to Ocaete.
Viste que algunos frenaron con Leo, otros salieron corriendo para el banco, otros salieron corriendo a Ocaete.
换句话说，每个人的反应都不同。
In other words, each one reacted differently.
o sea cada uno reaccionó de manera distinta.
但我的反应就像在点球大战中一样，寻找最后一个踢球的人。
But I reacted like in the penalty shootout, which goes to look for the last one who kicks.
Pero yo reaccioné como en la tanda de penales, que va a buscar al último que patea.
我找到了那个哭得那么厉害的人，我看到了那些人。
And I got to him who was there crying like that, I saw the people.
Y yo llegué a él que estaba allá llorando así, veía a la gente.
我想，然后格尔就到了，他们开始把所有东西扔到地板上。
Then Ger arrived, I think, and they started throwing everything on the floor.
Luego llegó Ger, creo, y se empezaron a tirar todo al piso.
我起鸡皮疙瘩了，白痴。
I'm getting goosebumps, idiot.
Se me mueve la piel de gallina, boludo.
然后 Paco Tau 和 Pablo 一起来看你。
And then Paco Tau came to see you with Pablo.
Y después vino Paco Tau a verte con Pablo.
他死了，朋友。
He's dead, friend.
Está muerto, amigo.
死的。
Dead.
Muerto.
我说……
I said...
Yo decía...
我们是世界冠军。
We are world champions.
Somos campeones del mundo.
我就这样死了。
I was left dead.
Yo quedé muerto.
我简直不敢相信。
And I couldn't believe it.
Y yo no lo podía creer.
他来到了更衣室。
He arrived at the locker room.
Llegó al vestuario.
马里托在哭，库蒂只是在哭，什么也没有。
And Marito was crying and Cuti was just crying and nothing.
y llorando estaba Marito y el cuti justo llorando y se nada.
我退休参加选拔。
I retire to the selection.
Me retiro a la selección.
我走了，就这样吧。
I'm leaving, that's it.
Me retiro, ya está.
那里的傻瓜们，就是这样，我已经实现了一切。
The fools who were there, that's it, I already achieved everything.
Los tontos que estaban, ya está, ya logré todo.
这是梦想。
It was the dream.
Era el sueño.
是的，然后巴勃罗来了，哭了，我记得他开始时眼睛里充满了泪水，这就是最……
Yes, then Pablo comes and is crying, I remember that he starts with his eyes full of tears and that's where the most...
Sí, después viene Pablo y está llorando, me acuerdo que empieza con los ojos llenos de lágrimas y ahí es donde más...
当我拥抱保罗时，我也哭了。
When I hugged Paulo, I also started to cry.
Cuando abracé a Paulo, además empecé a llorar.
我开始回忆。
I started to remember.
Empecé a acordar.
在英国的生活，我在那里遭受的苦难，我开始像个孩子一样哭泣。
Life in England, what I suffered there, I started crying like a child.
La vida en Inglaterra, lo que sufrí ahí, empecé a llorar como un niño.
一切，因为这是最好的。
Everything, because this is the best.
De todo, porque esto es lo máximo.
最重要的是，大家都很享受这次比赛。
Best of all, the group enjoyed the tournament.
Lo mejor de todo es que el grupo disfrutó el torneo.
他对我来说很享受。
He enjoyed it to me.
Lo disfrutó a mí.
这在训练中很明显，在每场比赛中都很明显。
It was noticeable in training, it was noticeable in every game.
Se notaba en el entrenamiento, en cada partido se notaba.
显然有紧张和一切，但就像每天一样......
Obviously there was nervousness and everything, but it was like every day...
Obviamente había nerviosismo y todo, pero era como que todos los días...
这很令人愉快，但不是……我的意思是，它感觉到了一种不同的氛围。
It was enjoyable, it wasn't... I mean, it felt a different vibe.
Se disfrutaba, no era... O sea, se sentía una vibra diferente.
是的朋友。
Yes friend.
Sí, amigo.
不，但对我来说...
No, but for me what...
No, pero para mí lo que...
让我们变得最好的是我们都在那里的大学。
What also made us best is being at the university that we all had there.
Lo que mejor nos hizo también es estar en la universidad esa que teníamos todos ahí.
真的很好。
It's really good.
Está re bien.
我们睡觉，我们吃饭，我们有我们的胜利，我们的田地。
We slept, we ate, we had our victory, our field.
dormíamos, comíamos, teníamos el victor nuestro, la cancha nuestra.
我走进球场，我记得决赛，我说……
I entered the court and I remember the final and I said...
Yo entré a la cancha y me acuerdo la final y dije...
你有没有看到我儿子通常写信给我，请不要用他的脚踢得太猛烈，你在我们和你一起踢球的俱乐部看到了这一点。
Did you see that my son normally writes to me, please don't play too aggressively with his feet, you saw that at the club we play with you.
Viste que normalmente mi hijo me escribe, por favor, no juegue muy jugado con los pies, viste que en el club te jugamos.
你全力以赴，胖子。
You give it your all, fat man.
Te das todo para arriba, gordo.
你谈论钓鱼，谈论生活。
You talk about fishing, about life.
Hablás de pescar, de la vida.
我在球场上说，我一生中在如此丑陋的地方打球，今天我要享受它。
And I said on the court, I played in such ugly places in my life, today I'm going to enjoy it.
Y yo entre la cancha dije, jugué en lugares tan feos en mi vida, hoy voy a disfrutar.
无论发生什么。
Whatever happens.
Pase lo que pase.
这根本没有影响我，无论是第一个进球还是第二个进球。
That didn't affect me at all, neither the first goal nor the second goal.
Eso no me afectó nada, ni el primer gol, ni segundo gol.
从这一天起，我就成长为一名弓箭手。
And from this day I grew as an archer.
Y desde este día crecí como arquero.
比赛结束了，我说……
The game ended and I said...
Terminó el partido y dije...
今天我是另一名守门员，事实上，我进步了一些。
Today I am another goalkeeper and, in fact, I improved a little more.
Hoy soy otro arquero y, dicho de hecho, mejoré un poco más.
并不是说我已经放松了，就是这样。
It's not that I've already relaxed, that's it.
No es que ya me relajé, ya está.
不，因为如果我能在3-3之后保持压力，朋友……
No, because if I could keep the pressure after 3-3, friend...
No, porque si pude mantener la presión después del 3-3, amigo...
我说，没有比这个压力更大的游戏了。
I said, there is no other game that has more pressure than this one.
Yo dije, no hay otro partido que tenga más presión que este.
在我的一生中，我可以参加欧冠决赛，这是世界上的另一场决赛，你知道那是什么感觉。
In my life, I can play in the Champions League final, the other final in the world, you know what it's like to experience.
en mi vida, puedo jugar final de Champions, la otra final del mundo, ya sabés lo que es experimentar.
如此轻松地获胜，距离输掉比赛还有 30 秒，这是独一无二的。
winning so comfortably and you are 30 seconds away from losing it will not have anything else like it.
ir ganando tan cómodo y estás a 30 segundos de perderla no va a tener otra cosa igual.
对我来说，我不了解你。
For me, I don't know about you.
Para mí, no sé de ustedes.
对我来说还有一些非常重要的事情。
For me also something very important.
Para mí también algo muy importante.
他们如何敢于踢点球等等。
how they dared to kick penalties and everything.
cómo se animaron a patear los penales y todo.
我就是这么说的。
That's what I said.
Eso lo dije yo.
在一次采访中，我记得一切，他们说，好吧，你还记得我扑出的点球吗？
In an interview I remember everything, and they say, well, do you remember the penalties that I saved?
Yo en una entrevista me acuerdo, todo, y dicen, bueno, ¿se acuerdan de los penales que atajé yo?
但他们给了我的伴侣九分之八。
But they gave my partner eight out of nine.
Pero a mi compañero me dieron ocho de nueve.
在两轮比赛中，荷兰队和这支球队之间是8或9。
In the rounds, between Holland and this, 8 or 9.
en las tandas, entre Holanda y esto, 8 o 9.
在厄瓜多尔的美洲杯上，我们也投入了一切。
In the Copa América in Ecuador too, we put everything into it.
En la Copa América en Ecuador también, metimos todo.
我记得我们第一次点球时，教练要求的。
I remember the first time we went to penalties that the coach asked.
Yo me acuerdo la primera vez que vamos a penales que el técnico preguntó.
他想踢我，不是我说我想踢，他像清理大蒜一样清理我，但是......
who wanted to kick and it's not that I said I wanted to, he cleaned me like a garlic, but...
quien quería patear y no es que yo dije que quería, me limpió como un ajo, pero...
你看，曾经人们不想或隐藏。
Once people, you saw, did not want or hid.
Una vez que la gente, viste, no quería o se escondía.
大家都说，我要踢，我要踢。
Everyone was, I want to kick, I want to kick.
Todos estaban, yo quiero patear, yo quiero patear.
在去法国之前，我问 Leo 是否需要浸泡一下，你看。
Before France I ask Leo if I do some soaking, you see.
Antes de Francia le pregunto a Leo si me hago un algo de empapé, viste.
WHO？
Who?
¿Quién?
WHO？
Who?
¿Quién?
他们怎么称呼它？
How do they call it?
¿Cómo le dicen?
苍蝇湿透了。
Fly soaked.
Vuela de empape.
在英国，他们说 embape。
In England they say embape.
En Inglaterra dicen embape.
吸收吧，朋友？
Soak up, friend?
¿Embape, amigo?
那是什么？
What's that?
¿Qué es eso?
In 到 P，带着 B。啊，in 到 P，是的。
In goes to P, with B. Ah, in goes to P, it is.
En va a P, con B. Ah, en va a P, está.
他说，上去，朋友，刹车，用力上去。
And he says, go up, friend, brake and go up, hard.
Y dice, va arriba, amigo, frena y va arriba, fuerte.
我的意思是，我明白了。
I mean, I got it.
Digo, lo tengo.
对太田的处罚。
Penalty against Ota's.
Penal contra el de Ota.
我跳起来，它就下来了。
I jump up, it goes down.
Me tiro para arriba, va abajo.
然后在这一轮中我稍微下降，然后它上升。
and then in the round I go a little bit down and it goes up.
y después en la tanda voy un poquito abajo y va arriba.
我告诉迭戈，你让我笑了。
I told Diego, you made me laugh.
Le dije a Diego, me remufaste.
你还记得前一天的训练吗？
Didn't you remember the previous day's training?
¿No te acordabas del entrenamiento del día previo?
朋友，我所有的进球都是他们通过点球打进的。
They scored all my goals, friend, from penalties.
Me metieron todos los goles, amigo, de penales.
是的，我记得。
Yes, I remember.
Sí, me acuerdo.
我就像踢我一样，告诉自己……他在踢我，就像今天我让你感觉很糟糕一样。
I was like kicking and told myself... He was kicking me up, like today I'm making you feel bad.
Yo me quedé como pateando y me decía… Me pateaba arriba, como hoy te hago almada.
不，我抓了一个。
No, I grabbed one.
No, agarré uno.
而且你还踢了我。
And you kicked me too.
Y vos también me pateaste.
你把我踢了个遍。
You kicked me up cross.
Me pateaste arriba cruzado.
你是否记得？
Do you remember?
¿Te acordás?
我没有砍过一个，伙计。
I didn't cut one, buddy.
No tajé uno, amigo.
我说，在点球大战中我罚得很好，把比分变成了2比1。
And I said, in the shootout I took the penalty really well, which made it 2 to 1.
Y yo dije, en la tanda me tiré re bien el penal, que me mete el 2 a 1.
朋友，如果我不从他嘴里说出这件事，我的心情就会非常低落。
And it went very down for me, friend, if I don't get it out of him.
Y me fue muy abajo, amigo, si no se la saco.
如果我攻击那个……哦，刺痛。
If I attack that... Oh, sting.
Si yo ataco ese... Oh, picadita.
厨师们，对吧？
The cooks, right?
Los cocineros, ¿no?
踢球的方式是怎样的。
What a way the kicks are going.
Qué manera que van las patadas.
我们不好。
We are not well.
Nosotros no estamos bien.
我什至不知道他扔掉了笔。
I didn't even know he was throwing away his pen.
Ni sabía que se tiraba el plumillo.
还有你的颜值，对吧？
And your level of appearance, right?
Y tu nivel de facha, ¿no?
你有一些观点，不是吗？
You had some points, didn't you?
Tuviste unos puntitos, ¿no?
我也告诉过你同样的事情，对吗？
I had told you the same thing, right?
Te había dicho lo mismo, ¿no?
松树是刚做好的，对吗？
The pine was freshly done, right?
El pino estaba recién hecho, ¿no?
那什么？
That what?
¿Eso qué?
你21号了吗？
Was your 21st?
¿Su 21 era?
不，最小的是。
No, the youngest was.
No, el más joven era.
是的，启示录玩家。
Yes, the revelation player.
Sí, el jugador revelación.
如果你像参加世界杯一样进入世界杯......
If you entered the World Cup as if you had played...
Si entraste al Mundial como si hubieras jugado...
朋友，如果我在你这个年龄踢球，那就是我必须参加世界杯的一场比赛，那就是我没有得到一个，我不给通行证。
Friend, if I play at your age, that is, I have to enter a game in a World Cup, that is, I don't get one, I don't give a pass.
Amigo, si yo juego a tu edad, o sea, tengo que entrar a un partido en un Mundial, o sea, no agarro una, no dim pase.
你进来撞翻了一辆自行车，它病了。
You came in and knocked over a bike and it's sick.
Entraste y tiraste una bicicleta y está enfermo.
是的，但它是在空中出现的，朋友。
Yes, but it came in the air, friend.
Sí, pero venía en el aire, amigo.
那么就完成吧，朋友。
Complete then, friend.
Completito entonces, amigo.
我病了，伙计，像那样玩等等。
I was sick, man, playing like that, etc.
Estaba enfermo, amigo, jugar así, etcétera.
难以置信，朋友。
Incredible, friend.
Increíble, amigo.
圆形的。
Round.
Redondito.
我不知道这个奖品的存在。
I didn't know the prize existed.
Yo no sabía que existía el premio.
不错，但是是圆的。
Good, but round.
Bueno, pero redondito.
是的，事实。
Yes, the truth.
Sí, la verdad.
此世间。
The world of this.
El mundo de esta.
小奖章。
The little medal.
La medallita.
感谢团队，朋友。
Thanks to the team, friend.
Gracias al equipo, amigo.
这要感谢团队。
That thanks to the team.
Eso gracias al equipo.
不，没关系。
No, it's okay.
No, está bien.
我相信在世界杯上没有人会说，不，这一场赢了这一场。
I believe that in the World Cup there is no one who says, no, this one won this one.
Yo creo que en el Mundial no hay uno que diga, no, este lo ganó este.
他赢得了一切，朋友。
He won it all, friend.
Lo ganó todo, amigo.
因为每一个...
Because each one...
Porque cada uno...
有点牛。
A little bit to the bull.
Un poquito al toro.
一开始他的脚踝问题并不顺利，但他打进了关键的点球。
Things didn't go well for him at first with his ankle, but he scored the key penalty.
No le fueron bien las cosas al principio del tobillo, pero metió el penalti clave.
这个在决赛中打破了它，你进入了墨西哥并向它施加了更大的压力，你打破了它。
This one broke it in the final, you entered Mexico and put more pressure on it, you broke it.
Este en la final la rompió, vos entraste en México y partiste más presión, la rompiste.
它是随荷兰一起带来的。
It has been brought with Holland.
Se ha trajido con Holanda.
鸡蛋并没有赢得荷兰队的点球。
The egg did not win the penalty with Holland.
El huevo no se ganó el penal con Holanda.
每个人都做了一些事情。
Everyone did something.
Todos hicieron algo.
莫利纳斜跑200米为荷兰队进球。
Molina ran 200 meters diagonally and scored the goal for Holland.
Molina corrió 200 metros en diagonal y hizo el gol de Holanda.
朱莉进来打破了它，伙计。
Juli came in and broke it, man.
Juli entró y la rompió, amigo.
决赛中的安吉利托看起来就像来自皇家马德里的安吉利托。
Angelito in the final looked like Angelito from Real Madrid.
Angelito en la final parecía Angelito del Real Madrid.
都写完了。
It was all written.
Estaba todo escrito.
这是你开心的时候穿的，对吧？
It's the one you wore when you were happy, right?
Es el que te pusiste en la happy, ¿no?
这是...
It is...
Este...
你知道为什么吗，朋友？
Do you know why, friend?
¿Sabes por qué, amigo?
他们都是这样，我不知道世界杯上是不是这样。
They were all like that, I don't know about it in the World Cup.
Es que estaban todos de ah, que no la sé en el Mundial.
他在那一刻进行了过滤，我们现在要进行过滤。
He filtered at that moment, we are going to have a filter now.
Filtro él en ese momento, vamos a tener filtro nosotros ahora.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
不，我要被烧死了，不，没有必要。
No, I was going to burn, no, there was no need.
No, yo iba a ardir, no, no había necesidad.
兄弟，你昏迷不醒。
Dude, you were unconscious.
Amigo, estabas inconsciente.
这就是你所得到的，肾上腺素，朋友。
That's what you got, the adrenaline, friend.
Es lo que te salió, la adrenalina, amigo.
还是傻了，没关系。
It's still stupid, it's fine.
Igual es tufetejo, está bien.
当然，只是当我在那个级别这样做时......
It's just that, of course, when I do this at that level...
Es que, claro, cuando hago esto en ese nivel...
他们会告诉你，他们会批评你，他们会告诉你，这不是社会的榜样。
They are going to tell you that they are going to criticize you, they are going to tell you that, it is not an example for society.
Te van a decir que te van a criticar, te van a decir eso, no es un ejemplo para la sociedad.
是的，我病了，确实如此……但你感觉失去知觉。
Yes, I'm sitting sick, which I am... But you feel unconscious.
Sí, estoy sentado enfermo, que soy... Pero te sientes inconsciente.
在阿根廷那个州，它是如何控制的。
in that state of Argentina how it does to control.
en ese estado de Argentina como hace para controlar.
伊莎贝尔有时我不得不解释说，不，我不是那样的人，你看，因为人们认为我是在某个值得庆祝的地方，你看。
And Isabel sometimes I had to explain that no, I'm not like that, you see, because people think I was somewhere to celebrate, you see.
Y Isabel a veces que tuve que explicar que no, que yo no soy así, viste, porque la gente piensa que estaba donde celebrar, viste.
后来我到达了我的俱乐部，他们告诉我......
I arrived there at my club later and they told me...
Yo llegué allá a mi club después y me decían...
守门员身体不太好，是吗？
The goalkeeper was not well, was he?
El arquero no estaba bien, ¿no?
我想我们所有人都回到了我们的俱乐部，但他们甚至没有祝贺我们，而是向我们询问了守门员的情况。
I think that all of us returned to our clubs and they didn't even congratulate us, they asked us about the goalkeeper.
Yo creo que todos nosotros volvimos a nuestros clubes y ni nos felicitaron, nos preguntaban por el arquero.
弓箭手病了。
The archer was sick.
El arquero estaba enfermo.
那个半疯狂的小弓箭手，对吧？
The half-crazy little archer, right?
El arquerito medio loco, ¿no?
这是我表现出平静的方式，我……我不知道，我感觉就像我在马德普拉塔时的样子，朋友。
It's my way of showing that I'm calm, that I'm... I don't know, I feel like myself when I was in Mar del Plata, friend.
Es mi manera de mostrar que estoy tranquilo, que soy... No sé, me siento yo cuando estaba en Mar del Plata, amigo.
我总是时不时地迸发出火花，但随之而来的是庆祝。
I always get a spark from time to time, but a celebration comes out of that.
Siempre se me sale alguna chispa de vez en cuando, pero de eso sale una celebración.
独特、高贵、善良。
Unique, noble, good.
Única, de noble, de bueno.
极好的。
Incredible.
Increíble.
谢谢，画画。
Thanks, Draw.
Gracias, Dibu.
这么多年了，还在这里。
Being so many years old, here.
Siendo tantos años, tomá.
画一下，谢谢。
Draw, thank you.
Dibu, gracias.
我今天引用你的话。
I quote you now today you here.
Te cito ahora hoy tú aquí.
世界杯的最后一个镜头是你，所以你这里有最后一张照片。
The last shot of the World Cup was you, so you have the last photo here.
El último tiro del Mundial fuiste vos, así que la última foto la tenés acá vos.
他放了哪一层，对吧？
What layer did he put in, right?
¿Qué capa metió, no?
不，这太棒了。
No, that's amazing.
No, eso es una pasada.
我有那件斗篷。
I have that cape.
Yo tengo una capa esa.
是的？
Yeah?
¿Sí?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你是在亚马逊买的吗？
Did you buy it on Amazon?
¿Lo compraste en Amazon?
他们没有给你吗？
Didn't they give it to you?
¿No se la dieron?
他们没有给你吗？
Didn't they give it to you?
¿No se la dieron?
是的，每人一个，但你为什么想要它？
Yes, one each, but why do you want it?
Sí, una a cada una, pero ¿para qué la queréis?
朋友，他们没有每人给一个。
Friend, they didn't give one each.
Amigo, no dieron una cada uno.
哦真的吗？
Oh really?
¿En serio?
我也没有再发现。
I didn't even find out anymore either.
Ya ni me enteré tampoco.
那才是值得的。
That was the one that was worth it.
La que valía era esa.
我有。
I have it.
Yo la tengo.
那就是赢了的那个。
That's the one that won.
Esa es la que ganó.
老实说，我不喜欢它。
I didn't like it, honestly.
A mí no me gustó, la verdad.
如果我们能让你思考。
If we can get you thinking.
Si te podemos poner a pensar.
明天看他怎么卖。
Let's see how he sells it tomorrow.
A ver cómo la sale a vender mañana.
你知道我不知道吗...？
Do you know that I didn't know that...?
¿Sabes que yo no sabía que...?
有人打赌只有一个。
There is a bet that there is only one.
Está la aposta que hay solo una.
我以为他们为每个获胜者制作了一个。
I thought they made one for each winner.
Yo pensé que hacían una por cada ganador.
世界杯只有一届。
There is only one World Cup.
Hay una sola Copa del Mundo.
当你赢得五场比赛时，我认为你就赢了。
When you win five, I think you win.
Cuando ganas cinco, creo que te la ganan.
当你赢得五场比赛时。
When you win five.
Cuando ganas cinco.
瑞士有一个金杯赛。
There is a Gold Cup that is in Switzerland.
Hay una Copa de Oro que está en Suiza.
这就是世界杯。
This is the World Cup.
Esta es la Copa del Mundo.
当然，你赢了，这才是真正的赢家。
Of course, you win, this is the real one.
Claro, vos ganás, esta es la real.
但随后它们会跟随您并从您手中夺走信息，并在触摸时给您回复。
But then they follow you and take it from you and give you the reply at the touch.
Pero después te siguen y te la sacan y te dan la réplica al toque.
如果他们改变了回报怎么办？
What if they changed the retuary?
¿Y si el retuario la cambiaron?
不，之前，不，在球场上，库纳布罗。
No, before, no, on the field, Cunabuero.
No, antes, no, en la cancha, el Cunabuero.
球场上有两个玻璃杯。
There were two glasses on the court.
Había dos copas en la cancha.
我不知道。
I did not know.
Yo no sabía.
我很惊讶……你来得更早，我对你的才华感到惊讶。
I was surprised... you came up earlier, I was surprised by the brilliance you had.
A mí me sorprendió... vos subiste antes, a mí me sorprendió el brillo que tenías.
不，是的。
No, yes.
No, sí.
极好的。
Incredible.
Increíble.
不，但对于狮子座来说也是如此，对吧？
No, but for Leo too, right?
No, pero para Leo también, ¿no?
稍后再获取。
Get it later.
Conseguirlo después.
他所取得的一切成就都因他一人而消失。
Everything he had achieved was missing alone.
Todo lo que había logrado le faltaba solo.
缺少了它的皇冠。
That was missing to crown it.
Faltaba eso para coronar.
多么好的一个例子啊。
What an example.
Qué ejemplo.
我最喜欢的是...
What I enjoyed the most was...
Lo que más disfruté fue...
当他赢得美洲杯冠军时。
when he won the Copa América.
cuando ganó la Copa América.
但当他赢得世界杯时，我更多的是为人民而不仅仅是为他。
But when he won the World Cup I felt more for the people, not just for him.
Pero cuando ganó el Mundial lo sentí más por el pueblo, no solo por él.
当他摆脱美洲杯刺时，我看到他更加放松了，朋友。
When he got rid of the Copa América thorn, I saw him more relaxed, friend.
Yo cuando se sacó la espina de la Copa América, ya lo vi más relajado, amigo.
随国家队夺冠的目标已经实现。
Objective that winning with the national team fulfilled.
Objetivo del que ganar con la selección cumplió.
我的脑子坏了。
My brain broke.
Se me estapó la nufra.
对我来说，这是为了国家，这太疯狂了。
And for me this was for the country, it was crazy.
Y esto para mí fue para el país, fue una locura.
是的，除了我们的生活方式之外，正如我们之前谈到的。
Yes, apart from how we live it, as we talked about before.
Sí, aparte como lo vivimos, como hablábamos antes.
美洲杯是的，我说过，他需要获胜。
The Copa América yes, I said, he needs to win.
La Copa América sí, dije, le necesita ganar.
在第一场比赛中，他在自己位置上的表现如何，我们的表现如何。
How he behaved from his place, how we came, in the first game.
Cómo nos comportó de su lugar, cómo veníamos, en el primer partido.
你的生活出了什么问题吗？
What's wrong with your life?
¿Qué le pasa con su vida?
我和墨西哥一起受苦，我和荷兰一起受苦，我和法国一起受苦。
with Mexico, I suffered with Holland, I suffered with France.
con México, sufrí con Holanda, sufrí con Francia.
当我一岁的时候，当我现在两岁的时候，我仍然用它作为动力。
When I turned one year old, when I turned two years old now, I still use it as motivation.
Cuando cumplí un año, cuando cumplí ahora dos años lo sigo usando de motivación.
我是世界冠军，你输了一场比赛，连续输了两场比赛，什么也没有发生。
I am world champion, you lost a game, two games in a row and nothing happens.
Soy campeón del mundo, perdiste un partido, dos partidos seguidos y no pasa nada.
我成为了与之抗争的世界冠军，我总是用它作为动力。
I became world champion fighting it and I always use it as motivation.
salí campeón del mundo peleándola y lo uso de motivación siempre.
一旦我说，要成为世界冠军，就这样，什么也没有发生。
Once I say, to be world champion, that's it, nothing happens.
Una vez que digo, a ser campeón del mundo, ya fue, no pasa nada.
我用它来继续成长。
I use it to continue growing.
Lo uso para seguir creciendo.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
¿Dónde va?
我想要另一份。
I would like to have another one.
Me gustaría tener otra.
我可以在炎热的天气里找一个然后放进去吗？
Can I look for one in the heat and put one in?
¿Puedo buscar una en el celo y poner una?
我的热心给了我吗？
Does my zeal give me?
¿Me da mi celo?
有一支球队连续两次夺得世界杯冠军。
There is a team that won two World Cups in a row.
Hay una selección que ganó dos Copas del Mundo seguidas.
两届冠军。
Two-time champion.
Bicampeón.
我保证，我会在那里退休。
I'll retire there, I promise.
Ahí me retiro, te lo prometo.
今天我告诉你们，我要退休了。
Today I tell you that I am retiring.
Hoy te digo que me retiro.
我今天告诉你们，在我们所有人中间。
I tell you today, among all of us.
Te lo digo hoy, entre todos.
世界杯结束后我就退役了。
I'm retiring after the World Cup.
Me retiro después del Mundial.
他已经老了，我说他愿意。
He's already old, I say he wants to.
Ya está viejo, digo que quiere.
对世界杯的兴趣将会阻止我。
This interest in the World Cup is going to stop me.
A mí me va a detener este interés en el Mundial.
一个混蛋。
An asshole.
Un pendejo.
我30岁开始打球，我的想法是什么？
I started playing when I was 30, what do I think?
Empecé a jugar a los 30 años, ¿qué creo?
我33岁退休了。
I have retired at 33.
Me he retirado a 33.
来吧，来吧。
Come on, come on.
Vete, vete.
多好的照片呀，朋友。
What a photo, friend.
Qué fotona, amigo.
我在那个盒子里有它。
I have it in that box.
La tengo en un cuadro ese.
我告诉你，事实是，它不会再进一步​​了。
I tell you, the truth is, it doesn't go any further.
Yo te digo, la verdad, no va más.
太阳在比里明格尔之后。
The sun was after being in Birimingale.
El sol era después de estar en Birimingale.
那也是最美好的时刻。
That was also the best moment.
Ese también fue el mejor momento.
我们不知道该去哪里。
We didn't know where to go.
No sabíamos por dónde ir.
他们要我们转身，但人们却不动。
They wanted us to turn, people weren't moving.
Querían que doblemos, la gente no se movía.
就在那一刻。
At that moment.
A ese momento.
漏斗是在那里制作的。
The funnel was made there.
Se hizo el embudo ahí.
因为在另一处我的另一边有高速公路。
Because in the other one I had the highway on the other side.
Porque en la otra tenía el autopista del otro lado.
那个地方，我不知道叫什么。
In that place, I don't know what it's called.
En ese lugar, no sé cómo se llama.
真的接近100度吗？
Towards 100 degrees, really?
¿Hacia 100 grados, de verdad?
我记得我们没水的部分。
I remember the part where we ran out of water.
Yo me acuerdo de la parte donde nos quedamos sin agua.
我开始喝香槟，听低音鼓。
I started drinking champagne and the bass drum.
Yo empecé a tomar champagne y al bombo.
这是他唯一做的事。
It was the only thing he did.
Era lo único que hacía.
完成。
Completito.
为了炒作和香槟。
To the hype and champagne.
Al bombo y champagne.
你知道我做了什么吗？
Do you know what I did?
¿Sabes lo que hice yo?
只见我爬到了前面。
I saw that I climbed up in front.
Vi que me subí arriba delante.
不，你有……你有谁？
No, you have... Who do you have?
No, vos tenés... ¿Quién tenés?
完全领先。
Fully ahead.
Adelante del todo.
薄饼。
The chapataba.
El chapataba.
还有睡觉。
And sleeping.
Y duriendo.
你手里拿着 Fernet。
You had Fernet in your hand.
Tenías Fernet en la mano.
我这样拉是因为我的小腿被烧伤了。
I pulled like that because I had burned my calves.
Tiré así porque me había quemado los gemelos.
当我上车的时候，我就这样支撑着自己。
When I got on, I supported myself like this.
Cuando me subí, me apoyé así.
当然，然后我开始给所有东西染色。
And, of course, then I started staining everything.
Y, claro, después empecé a manchar todo.
我脱掉衬衫。
I took off my shirt.
Me saqué la remera.
我开始清理蕨类植物，感觉很酷。
and I started to clean the fernet and it was cool.
y empecé a limpiar el fernet y estaba fresquito.
因为它脱皮了。
Because it was peeling.
Porque estaba que pelaba.
那天天气很热。
It was hot that day.
Hacía un calor ese día.
然后一个人穿上一件T恤。
And then one put in a t-shirt.
Y después uno metía una camiseta.
然后他最终得到了一件T恤。
And then he ended up with a t-shirt of one.
Y después terminó con una camiseta de uno.
一切都被告密了。
It was all snitched.
Estaba todo chivado.
但我把它装...
But I put it on...
Pero me la puse...
疯狂，中午2点。
Crazy, at 2 noon.
Una locura, a la 2 del mediodía.
因为它是红色的，朋友，红色的。
Because it was red, friend, red.
Porque estaba rojo, amigo, rojo.
前方我们疯狂地撞击。
Up ahead we hit, crazy.
Encima ahí adelante pegábamos, loco.
我就在你旁边。
I was next to you.
Yo estaba al lado tuyo.
你就像他一样。
You were like him.
Tú estabas como él.
我再也受不了了。
I couldn't take it anymore.
No podía más.
你有一张照片。
You have a photo.
Tienes una foto.
你有一张我不会扔掉的照片。
You have a photo that I'm not going to drop.
Tienes una foto que no la voy a caer.
我多么享受它。
How I enjoyed it.
Como he disfrutado.
但是凯利……除了看到人们哭之外，还有人跑到公共汽车旁边，他们跑了好几英里。
But Kelly... Apart from seeing people crying, there were people who ran next to the bus, they ran for miles.
Pero Kelly... Aparte de ver a la gente como lloraba, había gente que corría al lado del micro, corrió kilómetros.
然后他们就从桥上跳下去了？
And they jumped off the bridge?
¿Y se tiraban del puente?
哦，有两三个人跳下了桥
Oh, two or three jumped off the bridge
Uy, dos o tres se tiraban del puente
那里的小孩子们，哇，太疯狂了。
The little ones there, wow, crazy.
Los chiquitos ahí, aúpa, una locura.
对我来说，世界杯最触动我、触动我灵魂最深的就是主场比赛。
For me, what touched me the most about the World Cup, which touched my soul badly, was the home game.
Para mí lo que más me tocó de pos mundial, que me tocó el alma mal, fue el partido en casa.
与巴拿马？
With Panama?
¿Con Panamá?
或者那里...不，来自埃特罗角。
Or there... No, from Cabo Etero.
O ahí... No, desde Cabo Etero.
我们是怎么回来的，对吧？
How did we get back, right?
¿Cómo volvimos, no?
方尖碑扭转了局面。
The obelisk turned it around.
Lo dio la vuelta el obelisco.
戴上耳机，他说。
Put on your headphones, he said.
Pónganse los auriculares, dijo.
我当时想，嗯……不，我是在尾巴上。
I was like, well... No, I was with the tail.
Yo estaba como, bueno... No, con el cola estaba.
朋友们，我们正要到达那里，直升机已经打开了机翼。
Friends, we were getting there and the helicopters had their wings on.
Amigos, estábamos llegando ahí y los helicópteros tenían las alas prendidas.
所有土地，朋友。
All land, friend.
Todo tierra, amigo.
那张脸，朋友。
The face of that, friend.
La cara de eso, amigo.
他呼唤我们，他呼唤我们。
He calls us, he calls us.
Nos llama, nos llama.
就像在附近一样，对吧？
Like in the neighborhood, right?
Como en el barrio, ¿no?
一切，你看到了吗？
Everything, did you see?
Todo, ¿viste?
地方。
Place.
Sí, tío.
这里全黑。
All black here.
Todo negro acá.
这里全黑。
All black here.
Todo negro acá.
在哪里？
Where is?
¿Dónde está?
我仍然有我的恐惧。
I still had my fear up there.
Mi miedo igual tenía ahí arriba.
你就这样开始了这一轮。
You started the round like this.
Tú empezó la vuelta así.
我一生中从来都不是他们中的一员。
I had never been one of them in my life.
Nunca en mi vida me había suyado.
我们去 velicos 吧，五分钟就到了。
Let's go to the velicos, it's five minutes.
Vamos para los velícos, son cinco minutos.
我们四处走动，向人们打招呼。
We went around, greeted the people.
Dimos la vuelta, saludamos a la gente.
当他就这样转身侧身的时候。
When he turned like that on his side.
Cuando se ponía así de costado.
我们的没有碰到，下面有玻璃。
Ours didn't touch, it had glass below.
El nuestro no tocó, tenía vidrio abajo.
你知道我们的样子吗？
Do you know how we looked?
¿Sabés cómo mirábamos?
我不知道该去哪里寻找。
I didn't know where to look.
Yo no sabía por dónde mirar.
我的手出汗了。
My hand was sweaty.
Tuve la mano transpirada.
我们让你转身。
We turn you around.
Te damos la vuelta.
我们再去兜风吧，他说。
Let's go for another little ride, he says.
Vamos a otra vueltita, dice.
我们通过麦克风告诉他，去酒店。
And we told him through the microphone, go to the property.
Y nosotros por el micrófono le decíamos, anda para el predio.
技术员，你还记得技术员吗？
The technician, do you remember the technician?
El técnico, ¿te acordás del técnico?
朱莉一边唱歌一边想跳。
Juli was singing and wanted to jump.
Juli cantaba y quería saltar.
我有视频，但是...我们都打电话给他们。
I have the videos, but... We all called them.
Tengo los videos, pero... Todas las llamamos.
谁想要，谁最喜欢。
Whoever wants, whoever likes it the most.
A quien quiera, a la que más le guste.
我要迭戈的，白痴。
I'll take Diego's, idiot.
Yo me llevo la del Diego, boludo.
你是我的偶像，疯狂。
You are my idol, crazy.
Sos mi ídolo, loco.
我会以这个为目标。
I'll take the one for the goal.
Yo me llevo la del gol.
这三个我都要了
I'll take these three.
Estas tres me llevo.
听着，我把这个留在这里。
Look, I'll leave this one here.
Mira, esta te la dejo acá.
我会把它留在正交区给你。
I'll leave it for you in the ortho.
Te la dejo en el orto.